SAM MCCARTHY

MID FRONT END DEVELOPER



PROFILE

Passionate and driven software engineer focused on building unique digital experiences. Expertise building applications from the ground up utilising a variety of languages and tools. Confident in delivering exceptional results, mastering technologies & increasing system efficiency and performance.



https://sammccarthy.netlify.app/

CONTACT

6 0427 502 002

linkedin.com/in/sam-mccarthy-dev

github.com/sammyshows

1312/12 Queens Road, Melbourne 3004

SKILLS

Core

Tech

- Problem solving
- Pair programming
- Accountability
- Teamwork
- Patience
- Resourcefulness
- Organisation
- Diligence

- Vue
- TypeScript
- GraphQL
- TailwindCSS
- HTML/CSS
- Single-spa
- PostgreSQL
- Git & GitHub

EDUCATION



Web Development - Le Wagon

- Ruby on Rails HTML/CSS
- Ruby
- JavaScript
- APIs

- DOM
- Bootstrap
- Git
- GitHub
- React
- Figma
- SQLite
- PostgreSQL
- Active Record
- Scrum

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mid Front End Developer - Spotpass **NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT**

- Managed front end development and collaborated with backend team to build complete applications
- · Built a new internal portal using Micro Frontends and integrating Autho and GraphQL
- Developed fully responsive user interfaces with mobile-first principles in mind
- Worked autonomously in 2-weeks sprints
- Created and oversaw wireframe designs
- Wrote documentation for front end best practices

Junior Front End Developer - Spotpass

JUNE 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

- Developed fast user experiences with as little friction as possible
- Enhanced existing applications, adding new functionalities and features

Despatch Supervisor - AWM Clayton

JANUARY 2018 - DECEMBER 2020

- Led a team of 6 in national electrical wholesaler
- Managed 90+ logistics calls per day
- Implemented new strategies to minimise errors and improve efficiency

PROJECTS

ToGather

http://www.wegathertogather.com/

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, PostgreSQL, Meetup API

Team Skill: Scrum roles, Supportive, Ambitious, Creative

AirDoor

https://airdoor.herokuapp.com/

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, Figma, HTML5/CSS3, Cloudinary, Mapbox API

Team Skill: Team leader. Detail oriented. Communicative. Passionate